<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on spinning plates</title><link>https://spinningplates.net/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on spinning plates</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 14:23:18 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spinningplates.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Soar App Development With VS Code and Git</title><link>https://spinningplates.net/posts/soar-app-development-with-git/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 14:23:18 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://spinningplates.net/posts/soar-app-development-with-git/</guid><description>Security automation typically involves making connections to services - typically APIs both internal (e.g AD) and external (e.g. VirusTotal). Splunk&amp;rsquo;s SOAR solution has a large library of apps but it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty common requirement to connect to a service that doesn&amp;rsquo;t yet have an app.
SOAR makes it fairly easy to develop custom apps (connectors), which help abstract away some of the pain points of working with an API - including authentication, pagination, transformation of returned content and error handling.</description></item><item><title>Connecting the Unconnectable; Borrowing APIs from Single Page Applications</title><link>https://spinningplates.net/posts/borrowing-apis-from-single-page-apps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:49:16 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://spinningplates.net/posts/borrowing-apis-from-single-page-apps/</guid><description>A SIEM typically collects event data, runs detections, generates alerts and serves as a single pane of glass for security alerts. One of the fundamental types of event to ingest is malware alerts from endpoint antivirus and EDR solutions. Malware alerts may seem dull - no user behaviour analytics, no machine learning, but we very often read incident response reports where an attacker triggered AV/EDR alerts that were completely ignored, before eventually executing a ransomware attack or exfiltrating data.</description></item></channel></rss>